Manshi Raghuvanshi

Application Development Analyst

Email: raghuvanshiricha15@gmail.com

Phone: +918178282919

Address: Delhi, India

LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/manshi-raghuvanshi-175976140

A professional with 2.8 years of experience in interpreting, analyzing and transforming data for driving effective business solutions with complete understanding of Agile Methodology.

Working as PySpark Developer with hands on experience on AWS services.

Work History

Nov 2020 - Present

Application Development Analyst

Accenture, Bangalore - Pyspark Developer-

- Strong experience designing, developing, testing and delivering complete solutions using best practices and industry standards.
- Working on PySpark as Transformation tool.
- Developed spark applications in python(PySpark) on distributed environment to optimize the time required to load huge amounts of data using equivalent SQL Queries.
- Involved in converting Oracle SQL Queries into various Spark Actions and Transformations by Creating RDD and Dataframes.
- Analysed the sql scripts and designed it by using PySpark SQL for faster performance.
- Knowledge of creating and editing SQL queries.
- Responsible for creating the design documents, establish specific solutions, creating the Test Cases.
- Responsible for closing the defects identified by QA team and responsible for managing the Release process for the modules.

Nov 2018-Nov 2020

Associate Software Developer

Accenture, Gurugram - Pyspark & ETL Developer-

- Developed spark applications in python(PySpark) on distributed environment to optimize the time required to load huge amounts of data using equivalent SQL Queries.
- Involved in converting Oracle SQL Queries into various Spark Actions and Transformations by Creating RDD and Dataframes.
- Analysed the sql scripts and designed it by using PySpark SQL for faster performance.
- Knowledge of creating and editing SQL queries.
- Experience on migrating on Premises ETL process to AWS Cloud using Talend, Athena, RDS EMR.
- Source data ingestion into datalake.
- Coordinated with business customers to gather business requirements. And, interact with other technical peers to derive Technical requirements and delivered the BRD and TDD documents
- ETL solutions implementation and Interaction with client for specification of user requirement
- Knowledge of Hadoop, UNIX.

Education

Jul 2014 – Jun 2018

Domain Skills

- SQL
- Python
- Spark
- Unix
- Hadoop
- Amazon EMR
- Amazon Athena
- Amazon S3
- Amazon RDS